Vladimir Loskutov

Address: North Potomac, Maryland LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vloskutov Email: vladimir.losk90@g mail.com Website: https://enginerd.io

Github: https://github.com/englnerd

Summary

• Master of Science Degree in Computer Science and Engineering graduate with experience and knowledge of C, C++, and Python.

• A responsible and reliable individual with a desire to grow professionally and learn new technology.

Skills Summary

Skill	Tool (if applicable)
Programming Languages	C/C++ (4 years), Python (3y), SQL (1y), Java (1y), Perl (1y), Bash (3y)
Frameworks and Tools	Django (1 year), Bootstrap (1y), Elasticsearch (1y), Celery (1y)
Databases	SQLite (2 years), PostgreSQL (1y)
Web	HTML (6 years), CSS (6y), XML (6y), Liquid (1y), JavaScript (1y)
Platforms	Windows (6 years), Linux (4y)
Miscellaneous	Git (4 years), Mercurial (2y), MS Visual Studio (3y), Jekyll (1y)

Education

National Research University of Electronic Technology, Moscow, Russia	September 2013 – June 2015
Master of Science Degree in Computer Science and Engineering	GPA: 3.93/4.00
National Research University of Electronic Technology, Moscow, Russia	September 2009 – July 2013

Bachelor of Science Degree in Electronics and microelectronics

Professional Experience

Verifeed LLC, Washington DC

September 2016 – December 2016

Software Engineering Intern

- Software development and maintenance that is oriented on social intelligence analytics using Django, Bootstrap.
- Tools development and maintenance for generating reports using Django, PostgreSQL, Git.
- Agile Development and Test Driven Development.

Angstrem-Telecom, Moscow, Russia

September 2014 – May 2015

Junior Network Engineer

- Testing of embedded network devices (SoC RTL89xxC) based on OpenWrt and Octopus using Bash, iptables.
- Finding/Fixing bugs and maintaining code using C/C++, Git.
- Experience with RTL8188{C|CU|CUS}, RT8192{C|CU} wifi chips, RS-232 interface, U-Boot bootloader.
- Debricked routers using JTAG, Serial console.
- Fixing web interfaces using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Writing documentation for network equipment using MS Office.

Ltd. QDGroup, Moscow, Russia

July 2011 – August 2014

Technical Specialist

- Support for local office network in working condition, setting of office software and equipment.
- Configuration and maintenance of servers based on Windows and *nix, and other network equipment.
- Experience of using RS-232, RS-485 communications (corresponding protocols) for debugging (via serial console), debrick and firmware replacement of network devices.
- Installation and maintenance of access control system Apollo (running APACS). Firnware replacement, configuration, and interaction of Apollo's controllers.
- Configuration and maintenance of software (asterisk) and hardware PBX.

Projects

Housing Insights April 2017 – Present

The purpose of this project is to put better information in the hands of the decision makers and advocates for affordable housing. It will connect to relevant outside data such as public transit, zoning, and neighborhood characteristics to make it easy to consider all the relevant factors when prioritizing and coordinating work.

Used: Python, Flask API, Docker.

Tetris algorithm April 2015 – May 2015

Implementation Tetris algorithm for legalization of standard cell placement.

Class: Algorithms for Analysis & Optimization of Very-Large-Scale Integration & Systems on a Chip. Used: C/C++, STL, GLUT.

Kernighan-Lin algorithm

March 2015 - April 2015

Implementation Kernighan-Lin Algorithm for circuit partitioning.

Class: Algorithms for Analysis & Optimization of Very-Large-Scale Integration & Systems on a Chip. Used: C/C++, STL.

PlacerSA November 2014 – May 2015

Placer for standard cell placement (global & detailed) based on modified algorithm "simulated annealing" for VLSI and FPGA.

Used: C/C++, STL, GLUT, Batch scripting.